<!-- Resources used:
http://www.bluespot.de/en/Freiburg/categories/74-attractions/pois/2540-gerichtslaube?page=2
http://www.historisches-freiburg.de/innenstadt/bauwerke/martinstor/
https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geschichte_der_Stadt_Freiburg_im_Breisgau
https://www.geocaching.com/geocache/GC2D7V6_freiburger-geschichten-blutiges-ostern?guid=5ac1433e-f9af-4cdc-97f3-7d602c215061
https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geschichte_der_Juden_in_Freiburg_im_Breisgau
-->
<resources>
    <!-- App name [CHAR-LIMIT=20} -->
    <string name="app_name">Freiburg Guide</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Details</string>

    <!-- API key for google maps -->
    <string name="google_maps_key">AIzaSyDFJ0OXkYbA9fxdkrRA98S-476i42rekuE</string>

    <!-- Fragment titles [CHAR-LIMIT=20} -->
    <string name="history_fragment">History</string>
    <string name="jew_fragment">Jewish History</string>
    <string name="plaque_fragment">Plaques Translations</string>
    <string name="excursion_fragment">Excursions</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <!-- History of Freiburg -->
    <string name="ludwigshohe_name">Ludwigshöhe</string>
    <string name="lugwigshohe_description">"Ludwigshöhe on the Schlossberg (castle mountain).
        \n\nInscription:\n\"Ludwigshöhe. The duke of Zähringen, builder and founder of Freiburg in
        the year MCXX. Eternally grateful to the high descendant, our Ludwig great duke of Baden.
        \nFaithfully admired by the citizens of this oldest, first city of Zähringen.To joyously
        remember the VII. jubilee of the foundation. Lovingly dedicated on Ludwig Day Aug. MDCCCXX.
        solemnly inaugurated.\""</string>
    <string name="ludwigshohe_lat" translatable="false">47.993708</string>
    <string name="ludwigshohe_long" translatable="false">7.858219</string>

    <string name="citywall_name">Old City Wall</string>
    <string name="citywall_description">Pavement inscription, that indicates the course ofthe city
        wall south west of the Augustiner museum.\n\ninscription:\n\"Old city wall until ca.
        1825\"</string>
    <string name="citywall_lat" translatable="false">47.9937</string>
    <string name="citywall_long" translatable="false">7.852275</string>

    <string name="kaufhaus_name">Historic Merchants Hall</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_description">The Historic Merchants Hall in Freiburg dates to 1520-21.
        The front facade is decorated with statues and coats of arms that were sculpted between
        1520 and 1531 by Sixt von Staufen. The sculpted figures under baldachins show Emperor
        Maximilian I, King Philipp the Beautiful of Castile, Emperor Charles V and Emperor Ferdinand
        I - all Hapsburgs.</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_lat" translatable="false">47.994953</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_long" translatable="false">7.852890</string>

    <string name="gerichtslaube_name">Gerichtslaube</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_description">The Gerichtslaube where in 1498 the Reichstag was held
        \n\nA small gem from Freiburg’s past is located in the rear courtyard of the Old Town Hall,
        accessible from the Turmstrasse. It is the Gerichtslaube (court house), which was used for
        municipal matters at the beginning of Freiburg’s development. Between 1280 and 1300 the
        free-standing gabled house was built and originally used as a courtroom and a place where
        leading Freiburg citizens and aristocrats gathered. There was even a small jail in the
        cellar vaults.</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_lat" translatable="false">47.996076</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_long" translatable="false">7.849318</string>

    <string name="martinplaque_name">Plaques on Martins Gate</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_description">Plaques on Martin\'s Gate about its origins and the
        burning of witches\n\nInscription (left):\nMartin\'s Gate\nInitially Norsinger Gate.
        Oldest preserved fortified tower and gate from the medieval castle (beginning of 13th
        century). Restructured by C. Schäfer from 1901–03. Fully renovated in 1998.\n\n(right):
        \nBurning of witches\nMargaretha Mößmerin \nCatharina Stadellmentin\nAnna Wolffartin
        \nbeheaded and burned on 24th March 1599.\n\nThe City of Freiburg in Breisgau honour their
        memory at this location as well as all women, who fell victim to the witch persecutions.
        The suffering of these and all innocently tortured people is a living reprimand for
        tolerance and humanity.\n</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_lat" translatable="false">47.993725</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_long" translatable="false">7.848975</string>

    <string name="breisachertor_name">Breisach Town Gate</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_description">One of the few remaining remnants of the fortification
        of Freiburg by Vauban. The former entry to the Breisach gate is now the entrance for a
        restaurant.\n</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_lat" translatable="false">47.992242</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_long" translatable="false">7.847719</string>

    <string name="loretto_name">Loretto Chapel</string>
    <string name="loretto_description">"Cannon ball, that would have hit Louis XV on his observation
        post during his siege of Freiburg in 1744, stuck in the wall of Loretto's Chapel.\n"</string>
    <string name="loretto_lat" translatable="false">47.981375</string>
    <string name="loretto_long" translatable="false">7.838544</string>

    <string name="martinsgate_name">Martin\'s Gate</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_description">The plate above the archway commemorates until today the
        battle between the Freiburg militia, that was founded in 1793, and the revultionary troops
        from France. \n\nThe inscription:\n\"Monument to the volunteers of Freiburg under the major
        and city councilor Caluri and all the comrades-in-arms of Austria Breisgau, who honored
        themselves by their loyalty and bravery on 7th July 1796, for emperor and fatherland.
        Dedicated by their general baron von Duminique.\"</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_lat" translatable="false">47.993775</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_long" translatable="false">7.849031</string>

    <string name="munster_name">Tambur Graffiti at the Munster</string>
    <string name="munster_description">Graffiti by a German speaking drummer (tambur not tambour) of
        the Napoleanic Army 1810 on the outer wall of the munster choir.\n\nInscription:
        \n\"Tambur Hagenbuch 1810\"</string>
    <string name="munster_lat" translatable="false">47.995489</string>
    <string name="munster_long" translatable="false">7.852983</string>

    <string name="barricade_name">Square of the Last Barricade</string>
    <string name="barricade_description">Square of the last barricade during the 1848 Revolution
        near the Schwabentor.</string>
    <string name="barricade_lat" translatable="false">47.9929</string>
    <string name="barricade_long" translatable="false">7.854033</string>

    <string name="sternwald_name">Sternwald Memorial</string>
    <string name="sternwald_description">Memorial stone near Günterstal commemorating the freedom
        fighters who were killed on April 23, 1884 by government forces\n\nInscription:\n\"In
        memory of the fighters for freedom and democracy who fell in the fight against government
        forces on Easter Sunday, 1848.\"</string>
    <string name="sternwald_lat" translatable="false">47.970931</string>
    <string name="sternwald_long" translatable="false">7.852028</string>

    <string name="dortus_name">Mausoleum for Maximilian Dortus</string>
    <string name="dortus_description">The Mausoleum of Maximilian Dortus, German revolutionary of
        1848-49 shot by government troops at the very place in the Wiehre cemetry.</string>
    <string name="dortus_lat" translatable="false">47.985811</string>
    <string name="dortus_long" translatable="false">7.857147</string>

    <string name="soldiermem_name">Memorial for fallen Soldier (1848)</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_description">Memorial stone erected in the od cemetry for the soldiers
        who died during the siege of Freiburg in 1848. The grand duke ordered the stone, which was
        donated by the comrades of the fallen, to be turned so that the inscription could not be
        read from the road.\n\nInscription:\n\"In memory of those fallen at the assault on Freiburg
        on 24th April 1848, by their comrades-in-arms.\"</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_lat" translatable="false">48.000625</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_long" translatable="false">7.857602</string>

    <string name="bombattack_name">Marks of the WW I Bomb Attack</string>
    <string name="bombattack_description">Marks found on College Building I of the Freiubrg
        university, caused by the British bomb attack from 14th April 1917.</string>
    <string name="bombattack_lat" translatable="false">47.993697</string>
    <string name="bombattack_long" translatable="false">7.846094</string>

    <string name="university_name">Where The Imperial Eagle once soared.</string>
    <string name="university_description">Place at the wall of the university building where the
        eagle of the Third Reich once hung.</string>
    <string name="university_lat" translatable="false">47.993806</string>
    <string name="university_long" translatable="false">7.845594</string>


    <!-- Jewish history-->
    <string name="gurs_name">Gurs Memorial Sign Post</string>
    <string name="gurs_description">Memorial remembering the deportation of the Jews to the
        concentration camp in Gurs (South France) in the form of a sign post.</string>
    <string name="gurs_lat" translatable="false">47.995228</string>
    <string name="gurs_long" translatable="false">7.846164</string>

    <string name="buerckel_name">Wagner Bürckel Memorial</string>
    <string name="buerckel_description">Memorial at the place of the old synagogue in Freiburg for
        the so called Wagner-Bürckel campaign, where Jews from Baden and Palatinate regions were
        deported. \n\nThe inscription:\n\"On the 22nd October 1940, in only a few hours 6,504 jewish
        men, women and children from Baden and Palatinate were brought to central concentration
        camps and from there deported to camp Gurs in southern france. The oldest was 97 years old.
        Among them were about 300 jewish fellow citizens from Freiburg.\n\nThose who didn’t die
        because of hunger and diseases, were deported mainly to the eastern extermination camps
        Auschwitz and Maidanék from August 1942 on. Over 5,200 of those deported to Gurs died as
        victims of violence.\n\nToo many have then looked away, too few have resisted.
        This must not and will not be repeated.</string>
    <string name="buerckel_lat" translatable="false">47.995228</string>
    <string name="buerckel_long" translatable="false">7.846164</string>

    <string name="stolpersteine_name">"Stumbling Stones"</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_description">Stumbling Stones are memorial plaques found all across
        Freiburg in memory of each Jew who lived at that address. They include their names, birth,
        deportation and/or death date. This is the biggest cluster of six stumbling stones found at
        Eisenbahnstraße 66 commemorating members of the families Abraham and Grumbacher.</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_lat" translatable="false">47.997319</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_long" translatable="false">7.843346</string>

    <string name="blauebrucke_name">Memorial on the "Blaue Brücke"</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_description">Memmorial remembering the Jewish citizens from Freiburg
        and surroundings, who were deported to Gurs, France, on 22/10/1940.\n\nThe inscription:
        \n\"22/10/1940 over 450 Jews from Freiburg and the area were deported on the order of the
        National Socialist regional adminsitrator from the warehouse of the station of the time to
        the South French camp Gurs.\nMany of them already died in Gurs due to hunger and illnesses,
        most were murdered in the extermination camp Auschwitz.\n\nCity of Freiburg, October
        2003\"</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_lat" translatable="false">47.996014</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_long" translatable="false">7.840006</string>

    <string name="hebelschule_name">Memorial at the Hebel School</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_description">Memorial marker on the Hebel School in Freiburg, Germany.
        Jews from southern Germany were assembled in the schoolyard on October 22, 1940, immediately
        prior to walking to the nearby train station and then being transported to the concentration
        camp at Gurs, France.\n\nThe inscription:\n\n\"22/10/1940 here in the Hebel school yard many
        hundreds of Jews from South Germany were taken into custody and transported to Gurs for
        inihalation. \n\nIn memory and to always remember.\n\nNever again Fashism\nNever again
        National Socialism\nNever again xenophobia.</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_lat" translatable="false">47.997503</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_long" translatable="false">7.835736</string>

    <string name="vordtriede_name">"Käthe-Vordetreide-Weg" road sign</string>
    <string name="vordtriede_description">" Riesefeld is a new suburb of Freiburg, that took the
        opportunity of creating new street names to commemorate a Jewish citizen from WW II.
        \n\nThe inscription:\n\"K. Vortriede 1891–1964, jorunalist in Freiburg, Jew and Social
        Democrate was forced to emigrate in 1939. Author of letters critical of the time.\""</string>
    <string name="vordtriebe_lat" translatable="false">47.998016</string>
    <string name="vordtriebe_long" translatable="false">7.785265</string>

    <string name="oldsyn_name">Memorial for the destroyed synagogue</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_description">In front of the college building II of the Freiburg university
        is this memorial commemorating the old synagogue that stood here, that was destroyed during
        WW II.\n\n The inscription:\n \"Here stood the synagogue of the Israeli community of
        Freiburg. Built in 1870 it was destroyed 10th November, 1938, under a reign of violence
        and injustice.\"</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_lat" translatable="false">47.994504</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_long" translatable="false">7.846062</string>

    <string name="synplaque_name">Plaque on exterior wall of New Synagogue</string>
    <string name="synplaque_description">Memorial for the deportation of the Jews in Freiburg on 22
        October 1940, mounted on the exterior wall of Freiburg\'s new synagogue by the city of
        Freiburg in 1990.\n\nThe inscription:\n\"Earth, do not cover my blood and may my cry never
        be laid to rest. Job 16,18\n\nOn 22nd October, 1940 the Jewish citizens of city Freiburg
        were deportet to Gurs in Sotuh France under the NS-Diktatur regime. The city remembers in
        shame and grief. Freiburg, 22nd October 1990.\"</string>
    <string name="synplaque_lat" translatable="false">47.996394</string>
    <string name="syplaque_long" translatable="false">7.853619</string>

    <string name="newsyn_name">Plaque at entrance of the New Synagogue</string>
    <string name="newsyn_description">Plaque at the entrance to Freiburg\'s new synagogue, dedicated
        on November 5, 1987.\n\nInscription:\n\"The Freiburg Synagogue, after pillage and destruction
        during the NS-era, was re-edified and dedicated on November 5th, 1987.\n\nmy house will be
        called a house of prayer for all nations. Is 56,7\"</string>
    <string name="newsyn_lat" translatable="false">47.996394</string>
    <string name="newsyn_long" translatable="false">7.853619</string>

    <string name="schelenz_name">Schelenz Memorial</string>
    <string name="schelenz_description">Walter Schelenz, Mahnmal für die Opfer des
        Nationalsozialismus, 1975, –  Rotteckring, Platz der Alten Synagoge.</string>
    <string name="schelenz_lat" translatable="false">47.996078</string>
    <string name="schelenz_long" translatable="false">7.846633</string>

    <string name="annaplatz_name">Memorial of the Jewish Deportation at the Anna Square</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_description">Memorial for the Jewish deportation to Gurs at the Anna
        square in Freiburg\n\nInscription:\nCitizens from the Baden, Palatinate and Saar Region of
        Jewish beliefs or those who were declared Jewish by the inhuman race ideology were deported
        under the terror regime of National Socialism.\n\nThe abduction of the women, men and
        children from the Wiehre suburb concerned started in this place infront of all eyes, taking
        them to the South French concentration camp Gurs.\n\nMost died there from the inhuman camp
        conditions or were murdered later.\"</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_lat" translatable="false">47.985164</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_long" translatable="false">7.845881</string>

    <string name="herder_name">Memorial by Herder Edition</string>
    <string name="herder_description">Infront of the college building II of the Freiburg University
        is the memorial donated by the Herder Edition. \n\nThe two lying stone slabs have the
        inscription:\n\"In gratitude for the preservation of the city and munster on 27th November,
        1944 and in memory of the synagogue.\"</string>
    <string name="herder_lat" translatable="false">47.994575</string>
    <string name="herder_long" translatable="false">7.846214</string>

    <string name="cemetry_name">Momuent at the Jewish Cemetry</string>
    <string name="cemetry_description">Denkmal für die jüdischen Opfer der Gewaltherrschaft von
        1933 - 1945.\n\nInschriftentafel:\n\"Den jüdischen Opfern der Gewaltherrschaft
        1933 – 1945\"</string>
    <string name="cemetry_lat" translatable="false">48.012443</string>
    <string name="cemetry_long" translatable="false">7.828644</string>

    <string name="zwangsschule_name">Memorial Plaques at Lessing School</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_description">Memorial at the site of the compulsory school for Jewish
        children from Freiburg and the surrounding region that operated from October 21, 1936, until
        the Reichskristallnacht on November 10, 1938.\n\nfirst plaque:\n\"In memory and as warning
        \nCompulsory school for Jewish children\n\nJewish children from Freiburg and the surrounding
        region were taught here, because they were not allowed to attend general schools due to the
        racist laws. The students, their family and teachers were up against the national
        socialistic persecution and extermination politics. Thanks to brae people form the
        resistance many of these children could survive, but not their relatives.\nThe rescuers are
        an example of tolerance and civil courage to us. We mourn with the rescued for the murdered.
        \n✡\nFrom 21st October, 1936 to the Reichsprogromnacht on 10th November 1938 the compulsory
        school was accommodated in this building. From March 1939 until the deportations to Gurs in
        South West Fance on 22nd October 1940 lessons were held in the Jewish community house next
        to the synagogue at the Werthmann Square.\nOctober 2004\"\n\nsecond plaque:\n\"Over 60
        Jewish students kam\n\nfrom Breisach Raplh Eisemann, Bianca Gelsmar,Werner Geisamer, Günther
        Levy, Gretel Levy, Ruth Levy, Rosi Uffenheimer, Alex Wurmser, Alfred Weil, from Eichstetten
        Wittrude Hene, Ilse Weil, from Emmendingen Alfred Geismar, Else Geismar, Lore Grünebaum,
        Hugo Günzburger, Lisbeth Günzburger, Susi Günzburger, Herta Weil, Margot Weil, from Freiburg
        Heinrich Alpern, Alice Bloch, Rudolf Bloch, Walter Bloch, Herbert Burger, Marlene Goldstein,
        Gertrude Günzburger, Nelly Heilbrunner, Ilse Judas, Renate Kaufmann, Walter Kaufmann, Ruth
        Mayer, Max Plaut, Hanna Reichmann, Hede Reutlinger, Rita Rosenberger, Esther Schärf, Manfred
        Schärf, Leo Wertheimer, from Friesenheim Richard Levi, from Haslach Eugen Moses, Helmut
        Moses,\"\n\nthird plaque:\n\"from Ihringen Anneliese Judas, Karl Judas, Gretel Judas,
        Ingeborg Judas, Kurt Judas, Kurt Lion, from Kenzingen Alice Dreifuß, from Kippenheim Heinz
        Maier, Kurt Maier, Flora Wertheimer, from Müllheim Rolf Zivi, Wolfgang Zivi, from Offenburg
        Esther Cohn, Eva Cohn, Myriam Cohn, Susi Greilsheimer, Renate Haberer, Hedwig Hammel,
        Ingeborg Hammel, Rudolf Hammer, Kurt Hammel, Hannelore Kahn, Margot Kramer, Selma Maier,
        from Sohmieheim Egon Bloch, Lore Bloch, Margot Dreyfuss, from Villingen Lotte Schwab, …
        \n\nThe teachers\nDr. Alice Weil-Mendel, Alfred Kaufmann, Adolf Reutlinger, Klara Maier,
        Dr. Ilse Hamburger, Professor Maier and Herr Strauß.\nJuly 2006\"</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_lat" translatable="false">47.989753</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_long" translatable="false">7.847206</string>

    <!--Plaques transcriptions/translations -->

</resources>