<!-- Resources used:
http://www.bluespot.de/en/Freiburg/categories/74-attractions/pois/2540-gerichtslaube?page=2
http://www.historisches-freiburg.de/innenstadt/bauwerke/martinstor/
https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geschichte_der_Stadt_Freiburg_im_Breisgau
https://www.geocaching.com/geocache/GC2D7V6_freiburger-geschichten-blutiges-ostern?guid=5ac1433e-f9af-4cdc-97f3-7d602c215061
https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geschichte_der_Juden_in_Freiburg_im_Breisgau
https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Plaques_in_Freiburg_im_Breisgau
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colmar
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strasbourg
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Europa-Park
https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Staufen_-_Burgruine_Staufen.jpg
https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Schauinsland_(Schwarzwald)
https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Titisee
https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Schluchsee
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basel
-->
<resources>
    <!-- App name [CHAR-LIMIT=20} -->
    <string name="app_name">Freiburg Guide</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Details</string>

    <!-- API key for google maps -->
    <string name="google_maps_key">AIzaSyDFJ0OXkYbA9fxdkrRA98S-476i42rekuE</string>

    <!-- Fragment titles [CHAR-LIMIT=20} -->
    <string name="history_fragment">History</string>
    <string name="jew_fragment">Jewish History</string>
    <string name="plaque_fragment">Plaques Translations</string>
    <string name="excursion_fragment">Excursions</string>

    <!-- History of Freiburg -->
    <string name="ludwigshohe_name">Ludwigshöhe</string>
    <string name="lugwigshohe_description">"Ludwigshöhe on the Schlossberg (castle mountain).
        \n\nInscription:\n\"Ludwigshöhe. The duke of Zähringen, builder and founder of Freiburg in
        the year MCXX. Eternally grateful to the high descendant, our Ludwig great duke of Baden.
        \nFaithfully admired by the citizens of this oldest, first city of Zähringen.To joyously
        remember the VII. jubilee of the foundation. Lovingly dedicated on Ludwig Day Aug. MDCCCXX.
        solemnly inaugurated.\""</string>
    <string name="ludwigshohe_lat" translatable="false">47.993708</string>
    <string name="ludwigshohe_long" translatable="false">7.858219</string>

    <string name="citywall_name">Old City Wall</string>
    <string name="citywall_description">Pavement inscription, that indicates the course ofthe city
        wall south west of the Augustiner museum.\n\ninscription:\n\"Old city wall until ca.
        1825\"</string>
    <string name="citywall_lat" translatable="false">47.9937</string>
    <string name="citywall_long" translatable="false">7.852275</string>

    <string name="kaufhaus_name">Historic Merchants Hall</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_description">The Historic Merchants Hall in Freiburg dates to 1520-21.
        The front facade is decorated with statues and coats of arms that were sculpted between
        1520 and 1531 by Sixt von Staufen. The sculpted figures under baldachins show Emperor
        Maximilian I, King Philipp the Beautiful of Castile, Emperor Charles V and Emperor Ferdinand
        I - all Hapsburgs.</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_lat" translatable="false">47.994953</string>
    <string name="kaufhaus_long" translatable="false">7.852890</string>

    <string name="gerichtslaube_name">Gerichtslaube</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_description">The Gerichtslaube where in 1498 the Reichstag was held
        \n\nA small gem from Freiburg’s past is located in the rear courtyard of the Old Town Hall,
        accessible from the Turmstrasse. It is the Gerichtslaube (court house), which was used for
        municipal matters at the beginning of Freiburg’s development. Between 1280 and 1300 the
        free-standing gabled house was built and originally used as a courtroom and a place where
        leading Freiburg citizens and aristocrats gathered. There was even a small jail in the
        cellar vaults.</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_lat" translatable="false">47.996076</string>
    <string name="gerichtslaube_long" translatable="false">7.849318</string>

    <string name="martinplaque_name">Plaques on Martins Gate</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_description">Plaques on Martin\'s Gate about its origins and the
        burning of witches\n\nInscription (left):\nMartin\'s Gate\nInitially Norsinger Gate.
        Oldest preserved fortified tower and gate from the medieval castle (beginning of 13th
        century). Restructured by C. Schäfer from 1901–03. Fully renovated in 1998.\n\n(right):
        \nBurning of witches\nMargaretha Mößmerin \nCatharina Stadellmentin\nAnna Wolffartin
        \nbeheaded and burned on 24th March 1599.\n\nThe City of Freiburg in Breisgau honour their
        memory at this location as well as all women, who fell victim to the witch persecutions.
        The suffering of these and all innocently tortured people is a living reprimand for
        tolerance and humanity.\n</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_lat" translatable="false">47.993725</string>
    <string name="martinplaque_long" translatable="false">7.848975</string>

    <string name="breisachertor_name">Breisach Town Gate</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_description">One of the few remaining remnants of the fortification
        of Freiburg by Vauban. The former entry to the Breisach gate is now the entrance for a
        restaurant.\n</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_lat" translatable="false">47.992242</string>
    <string name="breisachertor_long" translatable="false">7.847719</string>

    <string name="loretto_name">Loretto Chapel</string>
    <string name="loretto_description">"Cannon ball, that would have hit Louis XV on his observation
        post during his siege of Freiburg in 1744, stuck in the wall of Loretto's Chapel.\n"</string>
    <string name="loretto_lat" translatable="false">47.981375</string>
    <string name="loretto_long" translatable="false">7.838544</string>

    <string name="martinsgate_name">Martin\'s Gate</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_description">The plate above the archway commemorates until today the
        battle between the Freiburg militia, that was founded in 1793, and the revultionary troops
        from France. \n\nThe inscription:\n\"Monument to the volunteers of Freiburg under the major
        and city councilor Caluri and all the comrades-in-arms of Austria Breisgau, who honored
        themselves by their loyalty and bravery on 7th July 1796, for emperor and fatherland.
        Dedicated by their general baron von Duminique.\"</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_lat" translatable="false">47.993775</string>
    <string name="martinsgate_long" translatable="false">7.849031</string>

    <string name="munster_name">Tambur Graffiti at the Munster</string>
    <string name="munster_description">Graffiti by a German speaking drummer (tambur not tambour) of
        the Napoleanic Army 1810 on the outer wall of the munster choir.\n\nInscription:
        \n\"Tambur Hagenbuch 1810\"</string>
    <string name="munster_lat" translatable="false">47.995489</string>
    <string name="munster_long" translatable="false">7.852983</string>

    <string name="barricade_name">Square of the Last Barricade</string>
    <string name="barricade_description">Square of the last barricade during the 1848 Revolution
        near the Schwabentor.</string>
    <string name="barricade_lat" translatable="false">47.9929</string>
    <string name="barricade_long" translatable="false">7.854033</string>

    <string name="sternwald_name">Sternwald Memorial</string>
    <string name="sternwald_description">Memorial stone near Günterstal commemorating the freedom
        fighters who were killed on April 23, 1884 by government forces\n\nInscription:\n\"In
        memory of the fighters for freedom and democracy who fell in the fight against government
        forces on Easter Sunday, 1848.\"</string>
    <string name="sternwald_lat" translatable="false">47.970931</string>
    <string name="sternwald_long" translatable="false">7.852028</string>

    <string name="dortus_name">Mausoleum for Maximilian Dortus</string>
    <string name="dortus_description">The Mausoleum of Maximilian Dortus, German revolutionary of
        1848-49 shot by government troops at the very place in the Wiehre cemetry.</string>
    <string name="dortus_lat" translatable="false">47.985811</string>
    <string name="dortus_long" translatable="false">7.857147</string>

    <string name="soldiermem_name">Memorial for fallen Soldier (1848)</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_description">Memorial stone erected in the od cemetry for the soldiers
        who died during the siege of Freiburg in 1848. The grand duke ordered the stone, which was
        donated by the comrades of the fallen, to be turned so that the inscription could not be
        read from the road.\n\nInscription:\n\"In memory of those fallen at the assault on Freiburg
        on 24th April 1848, by their comrades-in-arms.\"</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_lat" translatable="false">48.000625</string>
    <string name="soldiermem_long" translatable="false">7.857602</string>

    <string name="bombattack_name">Marks of the WW I Bomb Attack</string>
    <string name="bombattack_description">Marks found on College Building I of the Freiubrg
        university, caused by the British bomb attack from 14th April 1917.</string>
    <string name="bombattack_lat" translatable="false">47.993697</string>
    <string name="bombattack_long" translatable="false">7.846094</string>

    <string name="university_name">Where The Imperial Eagle once soared.</string>
    <string name="university_description">Place at the wall of the university building where the
        eagle of the Third Reich once hung.</string>
    <string name="university_lat" translatable="false">47.993806</string>
    <string name="university_long" translatable="false">7.845594</string>


    <!-- Jewish history-->
    <string name="gurs_name">Gurs Memorial Sign Post</string>
    <string name="gurs_description">Memorial remembering the deportation of the Jews to the
        concentration camp in Gurs (South France) in the form of a sign post.</string>
    <string name="gurs_lat" translatable="false">47.995228</string>
    <string name="gurs_long" translatable="false">7.846164</string>

    <string name="buerckel_name">Wagner Bürckel Memorial</string>
    <string name="buerckel_description">Memorial at the place of the old synagogue in Freiburg for
        the so called Wagner-Bürckel campaign, where Jews from Baden and Palatinate regions were
        deported. \n\nThe inscription:\n\"On the 22nd October 1940, in only a few hours 6,504 jewish
        men, women and children from Baden and Palatinate were brought to central concentration
        camps and from there deported to camp Gurs in southern france. The oldest was 97 years old.
        Among them were about 300 jewish fellow citizens from Freiburg.\n\nThose who didn’t die
        because of hunger and diseases, were deported mainly to the eastern extermination camps
        Auschwitz and Maidanék from August 1942 on. Over 5,200 of those deported to Gurs died as
        victims of violence.\n\nToo many have then looked away, too few have resisted.
        This must not and will not be repeated.</string>
    <string name="buerckel_lat" translatable="false">47.995228</string>
    <string name="buerckel_long" translatable="false">7.846164</string>

    <string name="stolpersteine_name">"Stumbling Stones"</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_description">Stumbling Stones are memorial plaques found all across
        Freiburg in memory of each Jew who lived at that address. They include their names, birth,
        deportation and/or death date. This is the biggest cluster of six stumbling stones found at
        Eisenbahnstraße 66 commemorating members of the families Abraham and Grumbacher.</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_lat" translatable="false">47.997319</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine_long" translatable="false">7.843346</string>

    <string name="blauebrucke_name">Memorial on the "Blaue Brücke"</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_description">Memmorial remembering the Jewish citizens from Freiburg
        and surroundings, who were deported to Gurs, France, on 22/10/1940.\n\nThe inscription:
        \n\"22/10/1940 over 450 Jews from Freiburg and the area were deported on the order of the
        National Socialist regional adminsitrator from the warehouse of the station of the time to
        the South French camp Gurs.\nMany of them already died in Gurs due to hunger and illnesses,
        most were murdered in the extermination camp Auschwitz.\n\nCity of Freiburg, October
        2003\"</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_lat" translatable="false">47.996014</string>
    <string name="blauebrucke_long" translatable="false">7.840006</string>

    <string name="hebelschule_name">Memorial at the Hebel School</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_description">Memorial marker on the Hebel School in Freiburg, Germany.
        Jews from southern Germany were assembled in the schoolyard on October 22, 1940, immediately
        prior to walking to the nearby train station and then being transported to the concentration
        camp at Gurs, France.\n\nThe inscription:\n\n\"22/10/1940 here in the Hebel school yard many
        hundreds of Jews from South Germany were taken into custody and transported to Gurs for
        inihalation. \n\nIn memory and to always remember.\n\nNever again Fashism\nNever again
        National Socialism\nNever again xenophobia.</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_lat" translatable="false">47.997503</string>
    <string name="hebelschule_long" translatable="false">7.835736</string>

    <string name="vordtriede_name">"Käthe-Vordetreide-Weg" road sign</string>
    <string name="vordtriede_description">" Riesefeld is a new suburb of Freiburg, that took the
        opportunity of creating new street names to commemorate a Jewish citizen from WW II.
        \n\nThe inscription:\n\"K. Vortriede 1891–1964, jorunalist in Freiburg, Jew and Social
        Democrate was forced to emigrate in 1939. Author of letters critical of the time.\""</string>
    <string name="vordtriebe_lat" translatable="false">47.998016</string>
    <string name="vordtriebe_long" translatable="false">7.785265</string>

    <string name="oldsyn_name">Memorial for the destroyed synagogue</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_description">In front of the college building II of the Freiburg university
        is this memorial commemorating the old synagogue that stood here, that was destroyed during
        WW II.\n\n The inscription:\n \"Here stood the synagogue of the Israeli community of
        Freiburg. Built in 1870 it was destroyed 10th November, 1938, under a reign of violence
        and injustice.\"</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_lat" translatable="false">47.994504</string>
    <string name="oldsyn_long" translatable="false">7.846062</string>

    <string name="synplaque_name">Plaque on exterior wall of New Synagogue</string>
    <string name="synplaque_description">Memorial for the deportation of the Jews in Freiburg on 22
        October 1940, mounted on the exterior wall of Freiburg\'s new synagogue by the city of
        Freiburg in 1990.\n\nThe inscription:\n\"Earth, do not cover my blood and may my cry never
        be laid to rest. Job 16,18\n\nOn 22nd October, 1940 the Jewish citizens of city Freiburg
        were deportet to Gurs in Sotuh France under the NS-Diktatur regime. The city remembers in
        shame and grief. Freiburg, 22nd October 1990.\"</string>
    <string name="synplaque_lat" translatable="false">47.996394</string>
    <string name="syplaque_long" translatable="false">7.853619</string>

    <string name="newsyn_name">Plaque at entrance of the New Synagogue</string>
    <string name="newsyn_description">Plaque at the entrance to Freiburg\'s new synagogue, dedicated
        on November 5, 1987.\n\nInscription:\n\"The Freiburg Synagogue, after pillage and destruction
        during the NS-era, was re-edified and dedicated on November 5th, 1987.\n\nmy house will be
        called a house of prayer for all nations. Is 56,7\"</string>
    <string name="newsyn_lat" translatable="false">47.996394</string>
    <string name="newsyn_long" translatable="false">7.853619</string>

    <string name="schelenz_name">Schelenz Memorial</string>
    <string name="schelenz_description">Walter Schelenz, Mahnmal für die Opfer des
        Nationalsozialismus, 1975, –  Rotteckring, Platz der Alten Synagoge.</string>
    <string name="schelenz_lat" translatable="false">47.996078</string>
    <string name="schelenz_long" translatable="false">7.846633</string>

    <string name="annaplatz_name">Memorial of the Jewish Deportation at the Anna Square</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_description">Memorial for the Jewish deportation to Gurs at the Anna
        square in Freiburg\n\nInscription:\nCitizens from the Baden, Palatinate and Saar Region of
        Jewish beliefs or those who were declared Jewish by the inhuman race ideology were deported
        under the terror regime of National Socialism.\n\nThe abduction of the women, men and
        children from the Wiehre suburb concerned started in this place infront of all eyes, taking
        them to the South French concentration camp Gurs.\n\nMost died there from the inhuman camp
        conditions or were murdered later.\"</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_lat" translatable="false">47.985164</string>
    <string name="annaplatz_long" translatable="false">7.845881</string>

    <string name="herder_name">Memorial by Herder Edition</string>
    <string name="herder_description">Infront of the college building II of the Freiburg University
        is the memorial donated by the Herder Edition. \n\nThe two lying stone slabs have the
        inscription:\n\"In gratitude for the preservation of the city and munster on 27th November,
        1944 and in memory of the synagogue.\"</string>
    <string name="herder_lat" translatable="false">47.994575</string>
    <string name="herder_long" translatable="false">7.846214</string>

    <string name="cemetry_name">Momuent at the Jewish Cemetry</string>
    <string name="cemetry_description">Denkmal für die jüdischen Opfer der Gewaltherrschaft von
        1933 - 1945.\n\nInschriftentafel:\n\"Den jüdischen Opfern der Gewaltherrschaft
        1933 – 1945\"</string>
    <string name="cemetry_lat" translatable="false">48.012443</string>
    <string name="cemetry_long" translatable="false">7.828644</string>

    <string name="zwangsschule_name">Memorial Plaques at Lessing School</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_description">Memorial at the site of the compulsory school for Jewish
        children from Freiburg and the surrounding region that operated from October 21, 1936, until
        the Reichskristallnacht on November 10, 1938.\n\nfirst plaque:\n\"In memory and as warning
        \nCompulsory school for Jewish children\n\nJewish children from Freiburg and the surrounding
        region were taught here, because they were not allowed to attend general schools due to the
        racist laws. The students, their family and teachers were up against the national
        socialistic persecution and extermination politics. Thanks to brae people form the
        resistance many of these children could survive, but not their relatives.\nThe rescuers are
        an example of tolerance and civil courage to us. We mourn with the rescued for the murdered.
        \n✡\nFrom 21st October, 1936 to the Reichsprogromnacht on 10th November 1938 the compulsory
        school was accommodated in this building. From March 1939 until the deportations to Gurs in
        South West Fance on 22nd October 1940 lessons were held in the Jewish community house next
        to the synagogue at the Werthmann Square.\nOctober 2004\"\n\nsecond plaque:\n\"Over 60
        Jewish students kam\n\nfrom Breisach Raplh Eisemann, Bianca Gelsmar,Werner Geisamer, Günther
        Levy, Gretel Levy, Ruth Levy, Rosi Uffenheimer, Alex Wurmser, Alfred Weil, from Eichstetten
        Wittrude Hene, Ilse Weil, from Emmendingen Alfred Geismar, Else Geismar, Lore Grünebaum,
        Hugo Günzburger, Lisbeth Günzburger, Susi Günzburger, Herta Weil, Margot Weil, from Freiburg
        Heinrich Alpern, Alice Bloch, Rudolf Bloch, Walter Bloch, Herbert Burger, Marlene Goldstein,
        Gertrude Günzburger, Nelly Heilbrunner, Ilse Judas, Renate Kaufmann, Walter Kaufmann, Ruth
        Mayer, Max Plaut, Hanna Reichmann, Hede Reutlinger, Rita Rosenberger, Esther Schärf, Manfred
        Schärf, Leo Wertheimer, from Friesenheim Richard Levi, from Haslach Eugen Moses, Helmut
        Moses,\"\n\nthird plaque:\n\"from Ihringen Anneliese Judas, Karl Judas, Gretel Judas,
        Ingeborg Judas, Kurt Judas, Kurt Lion, from Kenzingen Alice Dreifuß, from Kippenheim Heinz
        Maier, Kurt Maier, Flora Wertheimer, from Müllheim Rolf Zivi, Wolfgang Zivi, from Offenburg
        Esther Cohn, Eva Cohn, Myriam Cohn, Susi Greilsheimer, Renate Haberer, Hedwig Hammel,
        Ingeborg Hammel, Rudolf Hammer, Kurt Hammel, Hannelore Kahn, Margot Kramer, Selma Maier,
        from Sohmieheim Egon Bloch, Lore Bloch, Margot Dreyfuss, from Villingen Lotte Schwab, …
        \n\nThe teachers\nDr. Alice Weil-Mendel, Alfred Kaufmann, Adolf Reutlinger, Klara Maier,
        Dr. Ilse Hamburger, Professor Maier and Herr Strauß.\nJuly 2006\"</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_lat" translatable="false">47.989753</string>
    <string name="zwangsschule_long" translatable="false">7.847206</string>

    <!--Plaques transcriptions/translations -->
    <string name="lenel_name">Plaque for Otto Lenel</string>
    <string name="lenel_description">Plaque for Otto Lenel in front of his former house in Freiburg
        im Breisgau, Holbeinstraße 5\n\nInschrift:\n\"Professor of Roman rights Otto Lenel 1849–1935
        lived in this house from 1909 onwards.\"</string>
    <string name="lenel_lat" translatable="false">47.982048</string>
    <string name="lenel_long" translatable="false">7.845118</string>

    <string name="predigerkloster_name">Convent of Preacher</string>
    <string name="predigerkloster_description">Information plaque saying:\n\"Here stood the Convent
        for Preachers from the middle of the 13th century until its abolition in 1794, a glowing
        place for medieval research and religion. Even Albertus Magnus, one of the leading spirits
        of the Western World taught ecclesial and secular earls within these walls. 1492 emperor
        Maximilian was received a friendly reception. In the frigthful night of 27th November, 1944
        the remains of the convents sank to rubble.\"</string>
    <string name="predigerkloster_lat" translatable="false">47.997603</string>
    <string name="predigerkloster_long" translatable="false">7.848494</string>

    <string name="cityhall_name">Plaque at Old City Hall</string>
    <string name="cityhall_description">Plaque offering details about the new and old town hall as
        well as the court house:\n\n\"New Town Hall\nthe new town hall, located between Rathausgasse
        and Turmstraße was created in its current form by converting the old town houses
        \"Zum Phönix\"(the Phoenix) and \"Zum Rechen\" (the Rake). It was the main college building
        of the university between 1578 and 1774. The baroque furnished auditorium on the first floor
        and the original entry gate of the university, which is now found to the rear of the
        courtyard, where builtduring this period and survive to this day.\nThe building was home to
        various university institutes during the 19th century, e.g. anatomy. After the comprehensive
        extensions from 1896 to 1901 – a council hall corridor was added above the entry and the
        little bell tower – the city administration moved into the building. An extenvie renovation
        was completed in  2000/2001 thanks to donations from the township and economy.\n\nOld Town
        Hall\nThe Northerly situationed old town hall is linked to the new town hall by a bridge.
        The Freiburg town clerk worked here as early as the 13th century. The current house was
        built between 1556 and 1561. It was linked to two other town houses at a later date. All
        that remains from the initial construction is the crypt of the Klarissa Covenant founded in
        1272.\nThe building was burnt to the ground during the air raids on Freiburg in 1944. As
        part of the reconstruction from 1952 to 1958 trhee wings were added. It was thoroughly
        renovated in 2000/2001 thanks to donations by the township and economy.\n\nThe Court House
        \ntThe large and small court room have been in this house since 1328, which is now situated
        in the courtyard of the old town hall. Since 1480 the municipal court also meet here. In
        1497/98 the Reichstag, appointed by emperor Maximilan I., convened here. Since 1546 there
        have been many changes to this building. In 1863 they even added a third floor.\nDuring the
        air raids in November 1944 the court house was practically destroyed, leaving little more
        than its foundation walls. Only the stone-arched and iron doors shielded the archive wing
        and its complete equipment from 1553 leaving it mostly intact. The reconstructed building,
        partially financed by donations, can be used for receptions and sessons since 1979.\"</string>
    <string name="cityhall_lat" translatable="false">47.996102</string>
    <string name="cityhall_long" translatable="false">7.849038</string>

    <string name="baslerhof_name">Basler Hof</string>
    <string name="baslerhof_description">Commemorative plaque in the Basler Hof referring to Gestapo
        activities\n \n Inscription:\n \"In Memory\n The Basler Hof was the seat of the Secret State
        Police (Gestapo).\n Here people were summoned, interrogated, humiliated and tortured.\n We
        remember the victims of the national socialist terror regime and those citizens, who suffered
        in this house.\"</string>
    <string name="baslerhof_lat" translatable="false">47.996481</string>
    <string name="baslerhof_long" translatable="false">7.851881</string>

    <string name="threetrees_name">Three Trees for the Germany Unity</string>
    <string name="threetrees_description">Plaque in DietenbackPark, Freiburg:\n\"A growing memorial
        for the German Unity.\nThis green living memorial represents 25 years reunion. Germany is
        growing together, just like these trees.\nThe <b>pine tree</b> symbolises the East.\nThe
        <b>beech tree</b> symbolises the West.\nThe <b>oak tree </b> symbolises the unification of
        Germany.\nAn initiate by Werner Erhard\nUnder the patronage of the Federal Chancellor Dr.
        Angela Merkel\nSupported by the protective assosciation German Forest</string>
    <string name="threetrees_lat" translatable="false">48.000212</string>
    <string name="threetrees_long" translatable="false">7.800328</string>

    <string name="martin_name">Eugen Martin Memorial</string>
    <string name="martin_dscription">Plaque in Seepark Freiburg\n\"Eugen Martin installation\nEugen
        Martin (1925–2010), honorary citizen of Freiburg, gave the rose garten in Seepark new life.
        \nThe generous donation by the rose enthusiast Eugen Martin enabled the planting of over 150
        rose bushes in the rose garden created for the hauticultural show in 1986.\nThe rose garden
        was dedicated to its sponsor on 4th June 2011.\"</string>
    <string name="martin_lat" translatable="false">48.006872</string>
    <string name="martin_long" translatable="false">7.824419</string>

    <string name="fehrenbach_name">Memorial plaque for Constantin Fehrenbach</string>
    <string name="fehrenbach_description">at Schwarzwaldstraße 1 in Freiburg\n\n\"this house was
        built by and residence of\nConstantin Fehrenbach 1852–1926\nReich Chancellor of the Weimar
        Republic 1920–1921\"</string>
    <string name="fehrenbach_lat" translatable="false">47.990624</string>
    <string name="fehrenbach_long" translatable="false">7.854865</string>

    <string name="fehsenfeld_name">Fehsenfeld\'s Edition</string>
    <string name="fehsenfeld_description">Wallstraße 10, Freiburg: plaque: the edition of Friedrich
        Ernst Fehsenfeld (1853–1933) was seated here from 1890–1895, which published the ‘Freiburg
        Edition’ of the works by Karl May.</string>
    <string name="fehsenfeld_lat" translatable="false">47.992006</string>
    <string name="fehsenfeld_long" translatable="false">7.851907</string>

    <string name="hoffmann_name">Memorial Plaque for Dr. Hoffmann and his Wife</string>
    <string name="hoffmann_description">"Here lies the best and most faithful of all mothers Johanne
        Frederick Hoffmann née Bleymüller.\n* 19th August 1780\n† 24th March 1860\n\nHere lies an
        old man, who always followed his own research and dreams building on justice instead blindly
        trusting human law. Those who knew him bear witness to this. May the almighty judge offer us
        mercy and clarity.\nChristian august Hoffmann, dr. med.\n* 27th August, 1790. † 6th December
        1868."</string>
    <string name="hoffmann_lat" translatable="false">47.992637</string>
    <string name="hoffmann_long" translatable="false">7.86182</string>

    <string name="schlossberg2_name">Schlossberg: A Hint of History</string>
    <string name="schlossberg2_description">A Hint of History\nFreiburg and the Schlossberg were
        always of particular interest due to their situation. The Schlossberg bears its name with
        reason, as the Zähringer already erected their castle called “Burghaldenschloss” here in the
        11th century.\nThe securities around the  Burghaldenschlosswere tightened during the 30-year
        war. The canon square stems from this era. Freiburg was at the center of the conflict between
        Austria and France after 1648. The city was conquered in 1677 and incorporated together with
        this castle in a mighty fortress, designed by the architect Vauban by order of the French
        king Ludwig XIV. The fortification and castle were destroyed in 1744. The points of the
        wooden bars on the play ground commemorate the lances and spears and with them the war
        times, when soldiers used to stand guard on the fortress walls.</string>
    <string name="schlossberg2_lat" translatable="false">47.993273</string>
    <string name="schlossberg2_long" translatable="false">7.856948</string>

    <string name="schlossberg3_name">Schlossberg: Historic Walk Display 3</string>
    <string name="schlossberg3_description">Schlossberg of Freiburg Fortress\nHistoric walk\n Display
        number You are here o\n<b>The upper castle\n(Fort Saint Pierre)</b>\n<i>The strung out upper
            castle was the main part of the fortification and was built by engineers starting in 1679
            following plans by Sébastien de Vauban. It creates a constructional unit with the
            storage (Fort Carré oder Fort de l’Etoile), which enabled secure access from the lower
            castle. The actual upper castle incorporates storage and barracks.
        </i>\n\n<small>Isometrics of the upper castle “Fort de St. Pierre”. The main archway was
            found here  0: Austrian war archives Vienna. </small>\n\n<i>The Peterkirche (church)
            stood in the center of the courtyard. On the North the upper castle was shielded by a
            hornworm, to the North West by a bigger construction.\nThe path coming from the present
            Burghaldenring  secured the upstream route (Redoute du Chemie), which can still be
            traced easily in the terrain today.</i>\n\n<small>Ground plan of the upper castle with
            Salzbüchsle 0 and the upstream buildings “Plan et situation du Salspuchsle” found in:
            Austria. war archive Vienna. </small>\n\n<i>The castle access is gained via a
            architecturally complex created main gateway (porte Prinzipale)</i>\n\n<small>Ground
            plan and aspect of the main gateway of the upper castle “Plan et Elevation dune porte
            du Fort St. Pierre” l’Inspection du Geier Vincennes</small>\n\n<i> with upstream,
            triangular place of arms (place d’armes), which has also left its mark in the terrain
            (located display plaque). A deconstructible bridge went from the place of arms over the
            trench to the gateway, which lead through the inner wall. A covered path went along the
            outside of the trench (Chemie couvert), which was lowered towards the sloped exterior
            (glacis) and was secured by stockades. The process of the stockades can be traced
            following the concretee bollards.</i>\n\nWe offer our gratitude to Sparkasse
        Freiburg-Northern Breisgau for supporting the Freiburg Schlosserg e.V. board of trustees. We
        also offer our gratitude to Bernhard Sänger GmbH, construction company and company Dr.
        Lauck, surface technology for the manufacturing of these information boards.</string>
    <string name="schlossberg3_lat" translatable="false">47.996476</string>
    <string name="schlossberg3_long" translatable="false">7.865878</string>

    <string name="schlossberg4_name">Schlossberg: Historic Walk Display 4</string>
    <string name="schlossberg4_description">Fortress: Schlossberg of Freiburg\n<b>The Schlossberg as
        part of city history</b>\nFrom time immemorial the Dream valley of the Freiburg area created
        an important access point to the high Black Forest area. Thus the Schlossberg was a
        strategically important place to command the area from. It was seized in 1091 bei the dukes
        of Zähringen as their main castle and at its feet they founded the city of Freiburg.
        Following the 30-year war the by now Habsburgian city and the Schlossberg were sieged by
        French troops in 1677 and expanded to a modern fortress following the plans by the renown
        architect Vauban. Freiburg rejoined the Reich in 1697, but was reconquered in 1713 and 1744
        by the French, who before finally leaving in 1745 completed the fortification. This brought
        a distressing era of wars to a close, that cost 30,000 soldiers from Freiburg their lives.
        A new light forest park was created, pervaded by walkways, on the ruins of the Schlossberg
        fortress by the end of the 19th century. After WW II the history was sinking more and more
        into oblivion.\nThe Freiburg Schlossberg board of trustees, founded in 1997, set itself the
        target, to make the prominent meaning of the Schlossberg for Freiburg visible again. From
        the Schlossberg tower you can enjoy a wonderful view of the city and its history, which was
        erected by the board of trustees in 2002. On you way there you will encounter further
        information boards.\n\nThe sandstone plaque adjacent to this board was erected on the canon
        square at the start of the 19th century. The single sections of the Schlossberg fortress
        listed on the plaque are in part misleading. They are based on confusions and do not
        correspond with the terminology used by Vauban in his build of the construction. These can
        be found on the indications offered by the aluminium plaques mounted on the old
        construction.</string>
    <string name="schlossberg4_lat" translatable="false">47.993507</string>
    <string name="schlossberg4_long" translatable="false">7.857405</string>

    <string name="schlossberg10_name">Schlossberg: Historic Walk Display 10</string>
    <string name="schlossberg10_description">Schlossberg of Freiburg Fortress\nHistoric walk
        \nDisplay number 0 You are here o\n<b>Communication between castles via the
            <i>Salzbüchsle</i></b>\nThe castle fortification based on the plans of the castle
        building commissioner Vauban comprised of the upper castle (Fort St. Pierre und Fort Carré)
        on the highest elevation, the lower castle (Ancien Château) and Salzbüchsle (Fort de
        L’Aigle) situated between the two. The upper castle contained the main warehouse of the
        overall structure.\n\n<small>Plan view of the fortification with its communication.
            Extract from “Les forts de la Montagne de Fribourg”, ca. 1685.\nBibliothque de
            l’inspection du Genie Vincennnes [sic!].”</small>\n\nBecause of this they needed to
        install an efficient transport link between the three parts of the fortification. This link
        (la Communication) allowing two-way traffic was installed on the Schlossberg ridge around
        1680. A small reroute was attached to the link south of the Salzbüchsle. \n\n<small>Traverse
            section „Profil d la grande Communication dans l’Etat ou elle est présentement“. Circa
            1715, city archive of Freiburg.</small>\n\nTo enable communication during a siege, the
        Link was integrated into the castle and furnished by stockades on both sides. The wall
        trenches of this stockade paths could be excavated for the most part in good condition. In
        contrast the lower link was mostly destroyed in 1745. Comte de la Venerie called on the
        imperial manager of the fortification to reinforce the defenders of the construction after
        the siege in by the French army in 1713. The location of this display x marks the remnants
        of the second ring wall around the Salzbüchsle from 1728. \n\n<small>Second surrounding wall
            of the Salzbüchsle. „Plan de … Salzbüchslein comme als doit être renforcé” Mâchoire
            Auguste Comte de la Venerie 1723. Austrian war archive Vienna.
        </small>\n\n<small>Traverse section. „Profil du Saltzbüschlein et de des nouveaux ouvrages“,
            Melchior Auguste Comte de la Venerie 1723/28. Austrian war archive Vienna.
        </small>\n\nSpecial thanks to Sparkasse Freiburg Northern Breisgau for their support.\n</string>
    <string name="schlossberg10_lat" translatable="false">47.995364</string>
    <string name="schlossberg10_long" translatable="false">7.863346</string>



    <!-- Excursions -->
    <string name="strasbourg_name">Strasbourg</string>
    <string name="strasbourg_description">Strasbourg is the capital of Elsass, France.</string>
    <string name="strasbourg_lat" translatable="false">48.579444</string>
    <string name="strasbourg_long" translatable="false">7.738389</string>

    <string name="colmar_name">Colmar</string>
    <string name="colmar_description">Colmar is the third-largest commune of the Alsace region in
        north-eastern France.</string>
    <string name="colmar_lat" translatable="false">48.0766</string>
    <string name="colmar_long" translatable="false">7.358214</string>

    <string name="europapark_name">Europa Park</string>
    <string name="europapark_description">Europa-Park in Rust (Germany) is Germany\'s biggest theme
        park.</string>
    <string name="europapark_lat" translatable="false">48.267111</string>
    <string name="europapark_long" translatable="false">7.719194</string>

    <string name="staufen_name">Staufen</string>
    <string name="staufen_description">Staufen lies in Breisgau Hochschwarzwald (Black Forest),
        Baden_Württemberg. The city houses ca. 7800 citizens and is first mentioned in documents
        from the 7th century. With the castle ruin as its backdrop the historic city center comes to
        its full bloom. The Faust-legend supports its atmosphere, placing the meeting between Faust
        and the devil in a hotel right in the center of the city.</string>
    <string name="staufen_lat" translatable="false">47.886379</string>
    <string name="staufen_long" translatable="false">7.731944</string>

    <string name="schauinsland_name">Schauinsland</string>
    <string name="schauinsland_description">As the name hints at, the Schauinsland (literally: look
        into the land) offers a beautiful vista over the Black Forest and Breisgaul</string>
    <string name="schauinsland_lat" translatable="false">47.902243</string>3
    <string name="schauinsland_long" translatable="false">7.904642</string>

    <string name="titisee_name">Titisee</string>
    <string name="titisee_description">Titisee is a small lake and town in the Black Forest
        (Schwarzwald) in Baden-Württemberg.</string>
    <string name="titisee_lat" translatable="false">47.899143</string>
    <string name="titisee_long" translatable="false">8.153425</string>

    <string name="schluchsee_name">Schluchsee</string>
    <string name="schluchsee_description">The Lake of Schluch is a reservoir near St. Balsien in
        Breisgau-Hoschschwarzwald (Black Forest), Baden-Württemberg. It lies to the South East of
        the Lake of Titi and is the largest lake of the Balck Forest.</string>
    <string name="schluchsee_lat" translatable="false">47.842211</string>
    <string name="schluchsee_long" translatable="false">8.112609</string>

    <string name="basel_name">Basel</string>
    <string name="basel_description">"Basel  is a city in northwestern Switzerland on the river
        Rhine. Basel is Switzerland's third-most-populous city (after Zürich and Geneva) with about
        175,000 inhabitants.\n\nLocated where the Swiss, French and German borders meet, Basel also
        has suburbs in France and Germany. The cities agglomeration has ca. 830,000 inhabitants.
        \n\nThe city encorporates GrossBasel on the left (southwest) side of the Rhine and
        Kleinbasel (incorporating the old fishing village Kleinhüningen) on the right bank of the
        Rhine. The center of the old town lies in Grossbasel around the market square – where the
        town hall (built in 1504) stands – and the munster hill towering over the Pfalz-terrasse.
        The \"Mittlere Brücke\" connects the old city on both sides of the Rhine. The city center is
        freed from car traffic with public transport offered by tram. \n\nThe city is known for its
        various internationally renowned museums, ranging from the Kunstmuseum, the first collection
        of art accessible to the public in Europe, to the Fondation Beyeler (located in Riehen), and
        its centuries long commitment to Humanism, offering a safe haven among others to Erasmus of
        Rotterdam, the Holbein family, and more recently also to Hermann Hesse and Karl Jaspers.
        Basel has been the seat of a Prince-Bishopric since the 11th century, and joined the Swiss
        Confederacy in 1501. "</string>
    <string name="basel_lat" translatable="false">47.559601</string>
    <string name="basel_long" translatable="false">7.588576</string>


</resources>